Inventory of the Norman Allderdice Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Norman Allderdice Collection
1895-1984
2000C53
Allderdice, Norman, 1894-1961, collector.
135 ms. boxes, 1 oversize box (81 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Pamphlets, leaflets, and other printed ephemera, issued by right-wing, left-wing and other political organizations, and by governmental, business, labor, religious, educational and other organizations, relating to political, social and economic conditions in the United States and abroad, and especially to right-wing and left-wing movements in the United States.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research. Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives Audiovisual Specialist for further information.
Acquisition Information
The collection was acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2000.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1894 February 16 Born, McKeesport, Pennsylvania
1911-1915 Worked in open hearth department, Carnegie Steel Company, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania
1914 Graduated from Carnegie Institute of Technology
1916-1921 Superintendent, open hearth department, National Tube Company, Homestead, Pennsylvania
1921-1927 Manager, Pittsburgh office, Manning, Maxwell and Moore, Inc.
1927-1936 President and treasurer, Arch Machinery Company, Pittsburgh
1936-1939 Special agent, Frank M. Knox Company
1941? Retired to Tucson, Arizona
1961 July 27 Died, Tucson, Arizona
Scope and Content of Collection
The Norman Allderdice collection consists of pamphlets, leaflets, and other printed ephemera issued by right-wing, left-wing and other political organizations, and by governmental, business, labor, religious, educational and other organizations. The collection relates to political, social and economic conditions in the United States and abroad, and especially to right-wing and left-wing movements in the United States. The materials span a period of approximately one hundred years. They include English-language publications from publishing houses in Beijing, Hanoi, Moscow, and Pyongyang.
The bulk of the materials are organized in two series, each in rough alphabetical order. Within each series, most material is arranged by the name of the creator, although some items are arranged by title, subject, or country. Oversize materials are arranged separately at the end of the collection (box 135).
The desire to collect these materials grew out of Norman Allderdice's interest in individual freedom; conservative beliefs with respect to social and political issues; U.S. foreign relations, particularly with Russia; and opposition to any system of government that upholds autocracy.
The collection was acquired by Northern Arizona University in 1965. The university added printed matter gathered by a number of other collectors to Allderdice's collection, including much material published after Allderdice's death in 1961. The Hoover Institution Archives acquired this pamphlet collection in 2000. The Norman Allderdice collection of serial publications is available at the University of California at Davis.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
United States--Politics and government.; United States--Economic conditions.; United States--Social conditions.; Right and left (Political science); Conservatism.; Fascism--United States.; Antisemitism--United States.; Christianity and politics.; Anti-communist movements--United States.; Communism--United States.; Socialism--United States.; Radicalism--United States.; World politics--20th century.
Related Material
The Norman Allderdice collection of serial publications is available at the University of California at Davis.
Container List
- Series I
  - Aberg, Einar, 1917-1963. (Box-folder 1: 1)
    Leaflets and printed matter
  - Action in Kentucky (Folder 1: 2)
    (folder empty)
  - Adams, George, 1963. (Folder 1: 3)
    Form letter
  - Advertising Council, 1957. (Folder 1: 4)
    Clipping
  - Africa Fund, undated. (Folder 1: 5)
    Pamphlet
  - Aircraft Industries Association of America, 1956?. (Folder 1: 6)
    Printed matter
  - Alabama Committee to Support Your Local Police, undated. (Folder 1: 7)
    Brochure
  - Alabama Legislative Commission to Preserve the Peace, 1964. (Folder 1: 8)
    Civil rights bill
  - Alert, Seattle, Washington, 1961. (Folder 1: 9)
    Leaflets
  - Alert American Association, Los Angeles, California, 1963-1968. (Folder 1: 10)
    Affidavit, leaflets, and printed matter
  - Alerted Americans, Plymouth meeting, Pennsylvania, 1956-1958. (Folder 1: 11)
    Leaflets, printed matter, report, and research data
  - Alerted Americans, undated. (Folder 1: 12)
    Leaflet
  - Alexander, Holmes, 1957. (Folder 1: 13)
  - Alfange, Dean, undated. (Folder 1: 14)
    Statement
  - Allen-Bradley Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1973. (Folder 1: 15)
    Poster and printed matter
  - Allen, Donna, and Al Uhrie, "What's Wrong with the War in Vietnam?", undated. (Folder 1: 16)
  - The Alliance, New York, 1956. (Folder 1: 17)
    Form letter, leaflets, and miscellany
  - Allied Homeowners Association, Inc., 1959. (Folder 1: 18)
    Letter and printed matter
  - The Alternative: An American Spectator, Bloomington, Indiana, 1975. (Folder 1: 19)
    Letter about subscription and related materials
  - Alternative Press Centre, Toronto, Ontario, Canada, 1970s. (Folder 1: 20)
    Publication index
  - America First Committee, Chicago, Illinois, 1941. (Folder 1: 21)
    Address and brochure
  - America First, Palm Beach, California, 1941. (Folder 1: 22)
  - American Legion--Anti-Subversive Committee, Seattle, Washington, 1950s. (Folder 1: 23)
    Fact sheet about United Nations International Children Fund (UNICEF)
  - American Academy of Public Affairs, La Jolla, California, 1961. (Folder 1: 24)
    Letter
  - American-Asian Educational Exchange, New York, 1966-1967. (Folder 1: 25)
    Letters and minutes of meeting
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1962. (Folder 1: 26)
    Form letter and miscellany
  - American Association for the United Nations, 1962. (Folder 1: 27)
    Program for third biennial convention, New York City
  - American Association of University Professors Berkeley Chapter, California, 1968. (Folder 1: 28)
  - American Birthright Committee, Los Angeles, California, undated. (Folder 1: 29)
  - American Christian College, Tulsa, Oklahoma, 1969. (Folder 1: 30)
    Article by Billy James Hargis
  - American Civil Liberties Union, New York, 1940-1972. (Folder 1: 31)
    Annual reports, article, brochures, fact sheet, leaflets, and printed matter
  - American Coalition of Patriotic Societies, Washington, D.C., 1957-1960s. (Folder 1: 32)
    Brochures, clipping, form letter, leaflets, printed matter, and seminar paper
  - American Committee for Justice in the Middle East, Boulder, Colorado, 1973. (Folder 1: 33-34)
    Address, papers, special report, and testimony, 26th Annual Conference on World Affairs, University of Colorado
  - American Committee on Africa, New York, 1957-1958. (Folder 1: 35)
    Brochure and letter
  - American Committee on Immigration Policies, Washington, D.C., 1964. (Folder 1: 36)
  - American Committee on Free Cuba, Arcadia, California, 1960s. (Folder 1: 37)
  - American Committee on Keep Biafra Alive, Inc., 1969. (Folder 1: 38)
  - American Conservative Union, Washington, D.C., 1960s-1970s. (Folder 1: 39)
    Annual report, leaflets, form letters and letters from John M. Ashbrook, memoranda, and miscellany
  - American Council for Judaism, New York, 1953-1965. (Folder 1: 40)
    Articles, brochures, bulletin, newsletter, policy statements, printed matter, and miscellany
  - American Council--Institute of Pacific Relations, Inc., New York, 1945. (Box-folder 2: 1)
    Form letter, list of members of executive committee, and related materials
  - American Council of Christian Churches, New York, 1953, undated. (Folder 2: 2)
    Form letter, brochure, and miscellany
  - American Council of Christian Laymen, Madison, Wisconsin, 1950s-1960s. (Folder 2: 3)
    Brochures, leaflets, letters, printed matter, and miscellany
  - American Council on Public Affairs, 1943. (Folder 2: 4)
    Article and introductory notes
  - American Council to Improve our Neighborhood, 1955-1957. (Folder 2: 5)
    Annual report, brochures, leaflets, letter from Allen Wagner to Norman Allderdice, lists of board of directors and publications, memorandum, and press release
  - American Eagle Publishing Company, Dallas, Texas, 1962. (Folder 2: 6)
    Leaflets, printed matter, and miscellany
  - American Economic Foundation, New York, 1957-1970. (Folder 2: 7-8)
    Announcement, annual report, brochures, letters, press release, printed matter, speech, statement, and miscellany
  - American Education Association, 1958-1961. (Folder 2: 9)
    List of publications, note, and printed matter
  - American Emergency Committee on the Panama Canal, 1967. (Folder 2: 10)
    Form letter and petition to the United States Congress
  - American Enterprise Association, Washington, D.C., 1957-1960. (Folder 2: 11)
    List of publications and printed matter
  - American Eugenics Party, Los Angeles, California, 1967. (Folder 2: 12)
    Form letter and leaflets
  - American Federation of Labor Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, D.C., 1960-1970. (Folder 2: 13)
    Brochure, fact sheet, form letter, newsletter, printed matter, and statement
  - American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME Local 1695), California, 1973. (Folder 2: 14)
    Announcement
  - American Flag Committee, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1952; 1960-1967. (Folder 2: 15)
    Form letters and leaflets
  - American Forestry Association, 1959. (Folder 2: 16)
    Miscellany
  - American Freedom Train Foundation, Inc., Leesburg Pike, Virginia, 1975. (Folder 2: 17)
  - American Friends of the Captive Nations, 1959. (Folder 2: 18)
  - American Friends Service Committee (Box 3)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1955; 1957-1974. (Folder 3: 1-2)
      Brochure, form letters, newsletter, program, printed matter, reports, and miscellany
    - Pasadena, 1974. (Folder 3: 3-4)
  - American Heritage Protective Committee, San Antonio, Texas, 1960?, undated. (Folder 3: 5)
    Leaflet and miscellany
  - American Humanics Foundation, undated. (Folder 3: 6)
  - American Humanist Association, Yellow Springs, Ohio, 1960s. (Folder 3: 7)
  - American Indian Charter Convention, Chicago, Illinois, 1960-1961. (Folder 3: 8)
    Form letter, report, statement, and miscellany
  - American Indian Missions, Inc., Rapid City, South Dakota, 1975-1976. (Folder 3: 9)
    Brochure and form letter
  - American Institute for Economic Research, Great Barrington, Massachusetts, 1959.; 1961-1965.; 1970s. (Folder 3: 10)
    Form letter, printed matter, report, and miscellany
  - American Institute for Marxist Studies, New York, 1970-1974. (Folder 3: 11)
    Form letter, leaflet, list of accomplishments, printed matter, and miscellany
  - American Iron and Steel Institute, 1959. (Folder 3: 12)
    Printed matter and report
  - American Jewish Committee, New York, 1951; 1969. (Folder 3: 13)
    Article and fact sheet
  - American Jewish League against Communism, Inc., New York, 1962. (Folder 3: 14)
  - American League, New York, 1935. (Folder 3: 15)
  - American League against War and Fascism, New York, 1933-1935. (Folder 3: 16)
    Article, manifesto, and program
  - American Legion Americanism Committee, Atlanta, Georgia, 1960-1965. (Box-folder 4: 1-2)
    Brochure, catalog, instruction manual, leaflet, magazine, printed matter, report, and miscellany
  - American Legion
    - West Virginia headquarters, 1955. (Folder 4: 3)
      Remarks
    - Hemmingford, Nebraska, undated. (Folder 4: 4)
  - American Legion National Americanism Commission, 1958-1963. (Folder 4: 5)
    List of articles on communism appearing in the American Legion Magazine, memoranda, remarks, and statement
  - American Legislative Exchange Council, undated. (Folder 4: 6)
    Form letter and questionnaire
  - American Liberty Press, New York, undated. (Folder 4: 7)
  - American Librarians Association, 1960s. (Folder 4: 8)
    Bulletin
  - American Lobby, Washington, D.C., 1960s. (Folder 4: 9)
    Form letter and leaflet
  - American Medical Association, 1950s. (Folder 4: 10)
    Brochure and list of the board of trustees
  - American Mercury, McAllen, Texas, 1963. (Folder 4: 11)
  - American National Research, Inc., 1955. (Folder 4: 12)
  - American Nationalist, Inglewood, California, late 1950s - early 1960s. (Folder 4: 13)
  - American Nazi Party, Arlington, Virginia, early 1960s. (Folder 4: 14)
    Clipping, leaflet, and printed matter
  - American Progress Foundation, Los Angeles, California, 1950s. (Folder 4: 15)
  - American Opinion, 1958-1961. (Folder 4: 16)
  - American Party
    - Washington, D.C., 1975. (Folder 4: 17)
    - North Carolina, 1973-1974. (Folder 4: 18)
      Leaflet and letter
    - District of Columbia, 1972. (Folder 4: 19)
      Form letter and related material
  - American Patriots in Defense of Christian Observances, 1960s. (Folder 4: 20)
  - American Peace Crusade, 1951. (Folder 4: 21)
  - American Public Relations Forum, Inc., 1955. (Folder 4: 22)
    Bulletin, statement, and related materials
  - American Renaissance Book Club, Chicago, Illinois, 1960s. (Folder 4: 23)
    Leaflet, list of books, and printed matter
  - American Russian Institute, New York, 1947. (Folder 4: 24)
    Clippings and letters
  - American Security Council (ASC), Washington, D.C., 1961-1974. (Folder 4: 25-26)
    Annual report, brochure, form letters, invoice, newsletter, press release, printed matter, and miscellany
  - American Society of Planning Officials, 1950s. (Box-folder 5: 1)
    Pamphlets
  - American Southern Africa Council, Washington, D.C., late 1960s. (Folder 5: 2)
    Form letters, leaflet, and related materials
  - American States' Rights Party, 1965. (Folder 5: 3)
    Leaflets, newsletters, and remarks
  - American Survival Party, New York, 1960s. (Folder 5: 4)
  - American Taxpayers Union of California, Berkeley, California, 1971. (Folder 5: 5)
  - American Tract Society, undated. (Folder 5: 6)
  - American Youth for a Just Peace, Washington, D.C., 1970-1971. (Folder 5: 7)
    Form letter and article
  - Americanism, 1951-1971. (Folder 5: 8)
    Clipping, newsletter, printed matter, proclamation, and miscellany
  - Americanism Educational League, Buena Park and Inglewood, California, 1960s-1971, undated. (Folder 5: 9-10)
    Address, article, brochures, leaflets, and printed matter
  - Americanism--Lecture Services, 1954. (Folder 5: 11)
    Form letter and pamphlet
  - Americanist Research and Defense, 1961. (Folder 5: 12)
  - Americans against Union Control of Government, 1977. (Folder 5: 13-14)
    Form letters and leaflet
  - Americans for Agnew, Washington, D.C., 1972. (Folder 5: 15)
    Form letter and related materials
  - Americans for America, 1956. (Folder 5: 16)
  - Americans for Conservative Education, 1965. (Folder 5: 17)
  - Americans for Constitutional Action, Washington, D.C., 1959-1970. (Folder 5: 18)
    Address, annual and research reports, leaflets, list of ratings for U.S. senators, memoranda, printed matter, and miscellany
  - Americans for Democratic Action, Washington, D.C., 1960-1965. (Folder 5: 19)
    Clipping, form letter, printed matter, speech, and related materials
  - Americans for Freedom, Santa Barbara, California, undated. (Folder 5: 20)
  - Americans for Freedom of Speech, New Orleans, Louisiana, early 1960s. (Folder 5: 21)
  - Americans for Law and Order, Alton, Illinois, 1968. (Folder 5: 22)
  - Americans for Mental Freedom, Merced, California, 1961. (Folder 5: 23)
  - Americans for Middle East Understanding, New York, 1968. (Folder 5: 24)
  - Americans for National Security, 1963. (Folder 5: 25)
    Form letters and miscellany
  - Americans United, Silver Spring, Maryland, early 1970s. (Folder 5: 26)
  - Americans United Council, Long Beach, California, 1962-1963. (Folder 5: 27)
  - Americans United for Separation of Church and State, Washington, D.C., 1968. (Folder 5: 28)
    Clipping, printed matter, and remarks
  - America's Better Citizens Committee, 1952. (Folder 5: 29)
  - America's Future Incorporated, New Rochelle, New York, 1952-1967; 1975. (Box-folder 6: 1)
    Address, book reviews, correspondence, leaflets, memoranda, schedule, and related materials
  - Anderson, Tom, "Farm Ranch,", undated. (Folder 6: 2)
    Editorial article
  - Anglo-Saxon Committee, Burbank, California, 1947. (Folder 6: 3)
  - Animal Welfare Institute, Washington, D.C., 1972. (Folder 6: 4)
    Flyer
  - Another Mother for Peace, Beverly Hills, California, 1960s-1974. (Folder 6: 5)
    Address, annual report, and miscellany
  - Antarctica, 1954. (Folder 6: 6)
  - Anti-Comintern, 1938. (Folder 6: 7)
    Newsletter
  - Anti-Communism Voters League, undated. (Folder 6: 8)
  - Anti-Communism Book Club, Washington, D.C., 1960s. (Folder 6: 9)
  - Anti-Communist International, undated. (Folder 6: 10)
  - Anti-Communist League of America, 1960. (Folder 6: 11)
  - Anti-Communist Liaison (Committee of Correspondence), Arlington, Virginia, 1963-1964. (Folder 6: 12)
    Form letters
  - Anti-Defamation League
    - Chicago, Illinois, 1933. (Folder 6: 13)
    - B'nai B'rith, New York, 1943; 1955,; 1975. (Folder 6: 14)
      Annual report, bulletin, clipping, printed matter, and miscellany
  - Anti-War Movement, undated. (Folder 6: 15)
  - Arab Higher Committee for Palestine, New York, mid-1960s. (Folder 6: 16)
  - Argus Publishing Company, undated. (Folder 6: 17)
  - Arizona Captive Nations Committee, Phoenix, Arizona, 1966. (Folder 6: 18)
  - Arizona Civil Liberties Union, Phoenix, Arizona, 1964-1973. (Folder 6: 19)
    Announcement, form letter, and related materials
  - Arizona Coalition on Educational Policy, Phoenix, Arizona, 1969 or 1970. (Folder 6: 20)
  - Arizona Committee for Academic Freedom, 1962. (Folder 6: 21)
    Leaflets, message, and speech
  - Arizona Committee for Economic Freedom, Phoenix, Arizona, 1963, undated. (Folder 6: 22)
    Flyers, leaflet, and speech
  - Arizona Committee for the Abolition of Capital Punishment, Tucson, Arizona, 1966. (Folder 6: 23)
  - Arizona Committee of Taxpayers, Inc., Phoenix, Arizona, 1963. (Folder 6: 24)
  - Arizona Committee to Support our Local Police, Phoenix, Arizona, 1964. (Folder 6: 25)
  - Arizona Medical Association, 1962. (Folder 6: 26)
  - Arizona Messianic Witness, Inc., 1954. (Folder 6: 27)
  - Arizona News, 1957. (Folder 6: 28)
    Clippings
  - Arizona Republic, 1953; 1961,; 1965. (Folder 6: 29)
  - Arizona State University Young Socialist Alliance, undated. (Folder 6: 30)
  - Arizonans for America, Phoenix, Arizona, 1960-1961. (Folder 6: 31)
    Brochure, leaflet, and miscellany
  - Arizonans for General Walker, Phoenix, Arizona, 1960s. (Folder 6: 32)
    Newsletter and miscellany
  - Arizonans for Mental Freedom, Phoenix, Arizona, 1964. (Folder 6: 33)
    Excerpts from a lecture
  - Arizonans for Muskie, undated. (Folder 6: 34)
  - Arizonans for Safe Energy, undated. (Folder 6: 35)
  - Arms control, 1970. (Folder 6: 36)
    Articles
  - Assembly of Captive European Nations (ACEN), 1966. (Folder 6: 37)
    Booklet
  - Assembly of Unrepresented People, Washington, D.C., 1965. (Folder 6: 38)
  - Associates for Americanism, San Diego, California, 1955-1960. (Folder 6: 39)
    Form letter and report
  - Association for Research and Enlightenment, 1962. (Folder 6: 40)
  - Association for the Protection of our Water Supply, undated. (Folder 6: 41)
  - Association of American Physicians and Surgeons, 1956-1967. (Folder 6: 42)
    Letter, list of delegates, and papers
  - Association of Citizen's Council, Greenwood, Mississippi, 1956-1960s. (Folder 6: 43-44)
    Address, annual report, and fact sheet
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, Inc., undated. (Folder 6: 45)
  - Association to Repeal Abortion Laws, San Francisco, California, 1973. (Folder 6: 46)
  - Atlantic Union Resolution, 1969. (Folder 6: 47)
  - Atomic Energy Commission, undated. (Folder 6: 48)
  - Attack, 1974. (Folder 6: 49)
  - Australian Union of Students, 1974. (Folder 6: 50)
    Map, printed matter, and poster
  - Bach Medical Aid for Indochina Hospital Emergency Relief Fund, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1972-1973. (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Back Row Press, undated. (Folder 7: 2)
    Press news
  - Baez, Joan, 1963. (Folder 7: 3)
  - Ballistic Missiles, 1964. (Folder 7: 4)
  - Banks and money, 1956; 1974-1975. (Folder 7: 5)
  - Barnes, Richard, 1950s. (Folder 7: 6)
    Clipping, leaflet, letter, printed matter, and related materials
  - Barnett National Committee, 1964. (Folder 7: 7)
  - Barradas, Gerald, 1964. (Folder 7: 8)
    Memorandum
  - Barry Goldwater for President Committee, 1960. (Folder 7: 9)
  - Baxter International Economic Research Bureau, undated. (Folder 7: 10)
  - Bay Area Conservatives, San Francisco, California, 1964. (Folder 7: 11)
  - Bay Area Inter-Universities Committee on Vietnam, 1965. (Folder 7: 12)
  - Behavioral Research Council, Great Barrington, Mississippi, 1974. (Folder 7: 13)
  - Berachah Church, 1968. (Folder 7: 14)
  - Berkeley Campus Americans for Democratic Action, undated. (Folder 7: 15)
  - Berkeley Task Force, California, early 1960s. (Folder 7: 16)
  - Benni, William Charles, 1977. (Folder 7: 17)
    Sermon
  - Bentley, Elizabeth, 1955. (Folder 7: 18)
  - Biafra, undated. (Folder 7: 19)
    Sticker
  - Bible Institute on the Air, Mesa, Arizona, 1960s (Folder 7: 20)
  - Bicentennial Operation Alert, 1976. (Folder 7: 21)
  - Biggers, E. M., 1956. (Folder 7: 22)
  - Biggert, John W., Memphis, Tennessee, 1960s. (Folder 7: 23)
  - Bilderberg conferences, 1964. (Folder 7: 24)
    Article
  - Bill of Rights Commemoration Committee, undated. (Folder 7: 25)
    Printed copy of the preamble to the Bill of Rights
  - Biology as a social weapon, 1973. (Folder 7: 26)
  - Black Africa, 1963. (Folder 7: 27)
  - Black Community News Service, Harlem, New York, 1976. (Folder 7: 28)
  - Black Guards, San Francisco, California, 1970s. (Folder 7: 29)
    Leaflet and press release
  - Black Panther, 1970. (Folder 7: 30)
    Newsletters
  - Black Panther Party, San Francisco, California, 1970. (Folder 7: 31)
    Clippings, press release, and printed matter
  - Black Panther Party for Self Defense, undated. (Folder 7: 32)
  - Blackschleger, Hers, Sun Valley, California, 1960s. (Folder 7: 33)
  - Bob Jones University, undated. (Folder 7: 34)
  - Book catalogs.
    Includes related materials
    - 1973-1976 (Folder 7: 35-37)
    - 1953-1976 (Box-folder 8: 1-4)
    - 1971-1977. (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Bookmailer, 1960s. (Folder 9: 2)
  - Bourns, Inc., 1961. (Folder 9: 3)
  - Bricker Amendment, 1953-1955. (Folder 9: 4)
    Letters, memorandum, message, remarks, reports, statement, telegram, and related materials
  - Briggs, John, 1972. (Folder 9: 5)
  - British Columbia Civil Liberties Association, Vancouver, British Columbia, 1963. (Folder 9: 6)